<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-14T03:54:39+03:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fullstack Radar 2019</title><subtitle>Discovering the Fullstack technologies of tommorrow</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Interview With Haggai About Chaos Engineering</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Interview-With-Haggai-About-Chaos-Engineering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview With Haggai About Chaos Engineering" /><published>2019-04-10T14:23:45+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T14:23:45+03:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Interview-With-Haggai-About-Chaos-Engineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Interview-With-Haggai-About-Chaos-Engineering.html">&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/img/haggai-post.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Haggai Philip Zaguri&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
      Our DevOps architect, Haggai Philip Zaguri, helps make sense of Chaos Engineering.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cd-faq&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h6 class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Tell us a little bit about your background&lt;/h6&gt;
   &lt;p class=&quot;answer&quot;&gt;
      I started with IT / OPS in a small startup in Tel Aviv, at some point, we moved from the basement to new offices. I did everything, including IT, Ops &amp;amp; Scripts. We grew from a small company with just a few customers to an Internet provider.
      Initially, we turned to open source for financial reasons and from there it became a way of life and a way of thinking.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cd-faq&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h6 class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Was there a turning point in your career? A moment when you understand that you need to change direction or look at things from another perspective?&lt;/h6&gt;
   &lt;p class=&quot;answer&quot;&gt;
      The turnaround occurred when I started working at Tikal. I had to deal with a large number of clients that needed different solutions. My guiding principle was always good communication and a good understanding of the problem, helping me reach the right solution for the specific customer.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cd-faq&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h6 class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;What are you going to talk about at FTRD?&lt;/h6&gt;
   &lt;p class=&quot;answer&quot;&gt;
      The theme I'm going to talk about is Chaos Engineering, in general Chaos is a very sensitve word for me in the DevOps world where there's a lot of chaos, literally, and Chaos Engineering is basically dealing with this mess and putting things in place. Issues like monitoring &amp;amp; logging have more weight.
      In addition, the organizations we meet create a challenge of finding the correct path for them. Whether a parent company buys other companies and needs to organize them, or a company pivoting from Monolith to Microservices, suddenly needs new tools to meet current challenges.
      The field of Chaos Engineering started with Netflix, they based it on the theory of chaos from mathematics. According to this theory, it's possible to calculate the path of an object, but not the anomaly of when it'll come in contact with another object. Netflix had to deal with the early stages of cloud services, where concepts like Autoscale were not yet common. Therefore, they developed a set of tools, like an army of “monkeys”, that tries to deal with different parts of the app like security etc. This correlated well with their corporate culture of collective responsibility, so they started to create tools that create a  system outage and try to let developers deal with the problems. Some of these tools are less relevant today since there are fewer limits to resources on the cloud.
      Today there are more complex tools such as Kubeaudit or Kubehunter that can take them further in the development process to the CI / CD stages.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cd-faq&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h6 class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Are there any influencers in the field you are following?&lt;/h6&gt;
   &lt;p class=&quot;answer&quot;&gt;
      I follow Martin Fowler in particular and a number of people at ThoughtWorks. I also follow Adrian Cockcroft former Cloud Architect at NetFlix and Kelsey Hightower from Google.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cd-faq&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h6 class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;In your eyes, what is the most important thing when you look at the world of fullstack and development?&lt;/h6&gt;
   &lt;p class=&quot;answer&quot;&gt;
      The most important thing is communication both at the technological level and on the interpersonal level. Without cooperation between people, it is impossible to do things, especially in the fullstack world, which is advancing towards Full Cycle, requiring collective responsibility.
   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Our DevOps architect, Haggai Philip Zaguri, helps make sense of Chaos Engineering. Tell us a little bit about your background I started with IT / OPS in a small startup in Tel Aviv, at some point, we moved from the basement to new offices. I did everything, including IT, Ops &amp;amp; Scripts. We grew from a small company with just a few customers to an Internet provider. Initially, we turned to open source for financial reasons and from there it became a way of life and a way of thinking. Was there a turning point in your career? A moment when you understand that you need to change direction or look at things from another perspective? The turnaround occurred when I started working at Tikal. I had to deal with a large number of clients that needed different solutions. My guiding principle was always good communication and a good understanding of the problem, helping me reach the right solution for the specific customer. What are you going to talk about at FTRD? The theme I'm going to talk about is Chaos Engineering, in general Chaos is a very sensitve word for me in the DevOps world where there's a lot of chaos, literally, and Chaos Engineering is basically dealing with this mess and putting things in place. Issues like monitoring &amp;amp; logging have more weight. In addition, the organizations we meet create a challenge of finding the correct path for them. Whether a parent company buys other companies and needs to organize them, or a company pivoting from Monolith to Microservices, suddenly needs new tools to meet current challenges. The field of Chaos Engineering started with Netflix, they based it on the theory of chaos from mathematics. According to this theory, it's possible to calculate the path of an object, but not the anomaly of when it'll come in contact with another object. Netflix had to deal with the early stages of cloud services, where concepts like Autoscale were not yet common. Therefore, they developed a set of tools, like an army of “monkeys”, that tries to deal with different parts of the app like security etc. This correlated well with their corporate culture of collective responsibility, so they started to create tools that create a system outage and try to let developers deal with the problems. Some of these tools are less relevant today since there are fewer limits to resources on the cloud. Today there are more complex tools such as Kubeaudit or Kubehunter that can take them further in the development process to the CI / CD stages. Are there any influencers in the field you are following? I follow Martin Fowler in particular and a number of people at ThoughtWorks. I also follow Adrian Cockcroft former Cloud Architect at NetFlix and Kelsey Hightower from Google. In your eyes, what is the most important thing when you look at the world of fullstack and development? The most important thing is communication both at the technological level and on the interpersonal level. Without cooperation between people, it is impossible to do things, especially in the fullstack world, which is advancing towards Full Cycle, requiring collective responsibility.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Can Kubernetes Keep a Secret</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Can-Kubernetes-Keep-a-Secret.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can Kubernetes Keep a Secret" /><published>2019-04-07T14:23:45+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T14:23:45+03:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Can-Kubernetes-Keep-a-Secret</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Can-Kubernetes-Keep-a-Secret.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-omer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meet Omer Levi Hevroni&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
Meet Omer Levi Hevroni | Can Kubernetes Keep a Secret

Here are 3 things you probably didn’t know about him: He’s an open source junky, he has 2 adorable kids and he’s an OWASP groupie

Omer is the  DevSecOps engineer @ Soluto and he’s going to answer the question “Can Kubernetes Keep a Secret”. 

Want to know more secrets? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/fullstack-tech-radar-day-tickets-55203831145?aff=site&quot;&gt;Get your ticket&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Meet Omer Levi Hevroni | Can Kubernetes Keep a Secret</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Hacker-vs-Company-Cloud-Cyber-Security-Automated-with-Kubernetes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes" /><published>2019-04-04T14:23:45+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-04T14:23:45+03:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Hacker-vs-Company-Cloud-Cyber-Security-Automated-with-Kubernetes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Hacker-vs-Company-Cloud-Cyber-Security-Automated-with-Kubernetes.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-demi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Demi Ben-Ari&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
Meet Demi Ben-Ari | Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Demi is the Co-Founder &amp;amp; VP R&amp;amp;D @ Panorays, Google Developers Expert. With over 12 years of experience in building various systems both from the field of near real time applications and Big Data distributed systems. Co-Founder of the “Big Things” Big Data community and Google Developer Group Cloud. Demi’s talk “Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes” will focus on the ever-changing security threats in the cyber world and share how to build an infrastructure for security researchers that will allow them to concentrate on business logic and writing hacker “tasks”. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Meet Demi Ben-Ari | Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes Demi is the Co-Founder &amp;amp; VP R&amp;amp;D @ Panorays, Google Developers Expert. With over 12 years of experience in building various systems both from the field of near real time applications and Big Data distributed systems. Co-Founder of the “Big Things” Big Data community and Google Developer Group Cloud. Demi’s talk “Hacker vs Company, Cloud Cyber Security Automated with Kubernetes” will focus on the ever-changing security threats in the cyber world and share how to build an infrastructure for security researchers that will allow them to concentrate on business logic and writing hacker “tasks”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Full Cycle Development at Netflix</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Full-Cycle-Development-at-netflix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Full Cycle Development at Netflix" /><published>2019-04-01T14:23:45+03:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T14:23:45+03:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Full-Cycle-Development-at-netflix</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/Full-Cycle-Development-at-netflix.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-greg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Greg Burrell&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
We are excited to announce our first keynote speaker &lt;a href=&quot;/schedule/index.html#session-308&quot;&gt;Greg Burrell&lt;/a&gt; from Netflix!
&quot;The year was 2012 and operating a critical service at Netflix was laborious. Deployment frequency was measured in weeks. Operating a service involved staring at graphs and a lot of late-night heroics. Troubleshooting issues often devolved to bouncing the problem among teams. Today, in 2019, Netflix has grown to over 139M members enjoying our service all over the world. Deployments happen daily. The reliability of our service continues to improve and middle-of-the-night pages are rare. Our mission-critical services are owned and operated by small teams of developers with no dedicated test teams and no dedicated operations teams. How did we make this transition?&quot; 

Join us to learn about Netflix's journey from siloed teams to Full Cycle Developer model for building and operating services. 
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are excited to announce our first keynote speaker Greg Burrell from Netflix! &quot;The year was 2012 and operating a critical service at Netflix was laborious. Deployment frequency was measured in weeks. Operating a service involved staring at graphs and a lot of late-night heroics. Troubleshooting issues often devolved to bouncing the problem among teams. Today, in 2019, Netflix has grown to over 139M members enjoying our service all over the world. Deployments happen daily. The reliability of our service continues to improve and middle-of-the-night pages are rare. Our mission-critical services are owned and operated by small teams of developers with no dedicated test teams and no dedicated operations teams. How did we make this transition?&quot;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are Not A Commodity</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/You-Are-Not-A-Commodity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are Not A Commodity" /><published>2019-03-27T13:23:45+02:00</published><updated>2019-03-27T13:23:45+02:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/You-Are-Not-A-Commodity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/You-Are-Not-A-Commodity.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-jeff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jeff Meyerson&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
He’s coming to tell us the world of commodity engineering is coming to an end. 
Meet our second keynote speaker &lt;a href=&quot;/schedule/index.html#session-309&quot;&gt;Jeff Meyerson&lt;/a&gt;, Podcast host at sedaily!
“Developers are becoming more productive, more flexible, and more entrepreneurial. How does this impact you as an engineer? And how does it impact large companies who need a fungible set of engineers to maintain their software?”
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">He’s coming to tell us the world of commodity engineering is coming to an end. Meet our second keynote speaker Jeff Meyerson, Podcast host at sedaily! “Developers are becoming more productive, more flexible, and more entrepreneurial. How does this impact you as an engineer? And how does it impact large companies who need a fungible set of engineers to maintain their software?”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OnRadar Episode#1: A Config Keeping Tale</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/OnRadar-Episode-1-A-Config-Keeping-tale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnRadar Episode#1: A Config Keeping Tale" /><published>2019-03-21T13:23:45+02:00</published><updated>2019-03-21T13:23:45+02:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/OnRadar-Episode-1-A-Config-Keeping-tale</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/OnRadar-Episode-1-A-Config-Keeping-tale.html">&lt;p&gt;This episode (In Hebrew) will cover our encounters with config keeping, yes we were all under the impression that Kubernetes,ConfigMaps, and Secrets have solved all the worlds problems … well no, it seems like it’s still an issue.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/593293770&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This episode (In Hebrew) will cover our encounters with config keeping, yes we were all under the impression that Kubernetes,ConfigMaps, and Secrets have solved all the worlds problems … well no, it seems like it’s still an issue.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/middle-bg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Conversational UI</title><link href="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/conversational-ui.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conversational UI" /><published>2019-03-19T13:23:45+02:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T13:23:45+02:00</updated><id>https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/conversational-ui</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/updates/conversational-ui.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/people/royk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roy Kass&quot; class=&quot;post-speaker-image&quot; /&gt;
Conversational UI is the latest trend in the field of digital design that is focused on improving how people interact with systems. Industry leaders such as Apple, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, and Facebook are strongly focused on building a new generation of conversational interfaces.
Join us at #FTRD19 to learn more about this hot &lt;a href=&quot;/schedule/index.html#session-332&quot;&gt;You Used to Call Me on the Cellphone - Developing Conversational UI with Dialogflow&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Conversational UI is the latest trend in the field of digital design that is focused on improving how people interact with systems. Industry leaders such as Apple, Google, Microsoft, Amazon, and Facebook are strongly focused on building a new generation of conversational interfaces. Join us at #FTRD19 to learn more about this hot You Used to Call Me on the Cellphone - Developing Conversational UI with Dialogflow</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://fullstackradar.tikalk.com/cui.jpg" /></entry></feed>